RÉSUMÉ

John Krug

DoB: 12/01/1963

email: jh.krug@gmail.com	Address: Calle Adrián López Iriarte 27, Padul, Granada, 18640, Andalusia, España
Tel: +34 644 334 591. I don't answer calls from unrecognized numbers. Please message first using email, Signal, or Telegram, and we can get together.	LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jhkrug Twitter: https://twitter.com/jhkrug

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I'm an experienced information technology professional, with a 30-year career so far. I have worked in development, systems integration, support, deployment, data management, and technical documentation, often in leadership roles and in the public utility, private business, and higher education business areas. Most recently, I have been doing technical writing using a docs-ascode approach and thoroughly enjoying it.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Technical Writer, OutSystems, *July 2022 - Present*

I joined Technical Knowledge at OutSystems to work on product documentation for the OutSystems product suite. It's early days, but I'm involved with agile team leading, updating and writing documentation, and, learning the product set. We work with Zoom, JIRA and Confluence, markdown, git, VScode, and GitHub. There is daily contact with subject matter experts and product owners to move work forwards. It's a great team and I'm enjoying being back in full-time work. This is a fully remote-only role.

Consultant, Independent, May 2017 - July 2022

Since moving to Spain I have worked mainly on behalf of the University of Leeds. This was a fully remote role. I developed a set of Alma and Primo analytics training materials that their staff could use. We agreed that the material could be Creative Commons licensed. The training materials website at https://libtics.org is the result of that work.

The training materials are hosted using Netlify, they are written using AsciiDoc markup and processed to generate libtics.org using the Antora static site generator. The materials consist of documentation and accompanying video material. The source is at https://gitlab.com/libtics. The

project uses a docs-as-code approach.

In April 2018, I helped organize and presented at a training workshop on Alma Analytics for UK Ex Libris users in London.

Systems and Analytics Manager, Lancaster University Library, *April 2002 - March 2017*

I spent 15 happy years at Lancaster University Library starting as the Library Systems Coordinator. The first role was the implementation of the Aleph library management system from Ex Libris. This was used to replace a custom in-house system. Other Ex Libris systems were implemented and integrated; Metalib and SFX from 2004, Primo from 2010, and the new cloud-based library management system, Alma from 2012/13.

For IGeLU[1] and ELUNA[2], I established the first Analytics working group[3]. The group was established to promote the use of Alma Analytics in libraries and to work through issues with Ex Libris regarding analytics products they provided. This involved coordinating the effort of about 14 library professionals around the world in many time zones.

Key achievements: Implementing Aleph, Alma, and Primo. ILM Level 5 Award in leadership and management. First coordinator of the IGeLU and ELUNA Analytics working group. Lancaster University staff award for outstanding achievement.

Technical Director, Xinetica Ltd, 1996 - March 2002

With a small group of colleagues, I started an information systems integration consultancy. Alongside the business management aspects, I did consultancy work and a major systems implementation for ASDA in Leeds. I also worked at the Financial Services Authority, the UK government's financial services regulator, in London, notably on a Y2K migration and testing project. Xinetica did well for a few years then a combination of the first internet bubble collapse and internal divisions closed us down.

Protek Ltd, Technical Consultant, 1994-1996

I worked mainly at North West Water supporting Unix (IBM's AIX) hardware and software infrastructure and developing software on their behalf. I designed and managed a major operating system upgrade that needed to take place over a single weekend and at multiple sites.

Barclays de Zoet Wedd, Systems Administrator, 1992-1993

I supported Sun Microsystems Unix workstations running a variety of financial trading software for the foreign exchange derivatives desk.

NTSC, Technician, 1991

I worked to help the NTSC's[4] efforts in promoting the uses of parallel processing using the INMOS transputer. I followed up on my M.Sc. dissertation work with further work with British Steel in computer vision.

British Army, Royal Artillery, 1983-1986

I worked in a mortar locating radar troop. I can drive an armored personnel carrier if necessary. :-)

EDUCATION

1990-1991 - University of Sheffield, M.Sc. Software Systems Technology

1985-1989 - Open University (UK), a variety of undergraduate courses at different levels, mainly mathematics and computing. I never got around to finishing off an undergraduate degree, but the individual course results were good enough to earn a place on an M.Sc. at the University of Sheffield.

SKILLS

I have used and integrated many information technologies, databases, networks, and tools over the years. I am familiar with Unix/Linux and the shell and have programmed in many languages over the years (Assembler, C, OCCAM, SQL, Lua, Python, Shell, etc., etc.). As well as this, I have written much technical material and documentation. Much of this work has been to do with administration/integration automation or data wrangling of some sort. Many times, I have learned new technologies and used and implemented them where I have been working.

In more recent times I have worked with Oracle Data Visualization and OBIEE as part of Alma and Primo Analytics, built into Ex Libris's library management offering. I've also worked with Tableau while at Lancaster for visual data reporting.

I have worked both independently, and closely with others, in large and small organizations and teams, in offices and remotely across the world and timezones. I have been an employee, a director/owner, and a manager on different occasions. I am currently working in an agile documentation development team using JIRA and Confluence.

REFERENCES

From Masud Khokhar:

https://john.libtics.org/public/references/MK-JK-ref.pdf

From David Summers:

https://john.libtics.org/public/references/DS-JK-ref.pdf

OTITED

UTHER
I have a very occasional blog, currently at https://jhkrug.github.io.

FOOTNOTES

- 1 International Group of Ex Libris Users
- 2 Ex Libris Users of North America
- 3 Analytics SIWG (Special Interest Working Group) at https://igelu.org/products-and-initiatives/ communities-of-practice/analytics/
- 4 National Transputer Support Centre in Sheffield. A body established with UK government funding to promote parallel processing using the INMOS Transputer. The Transputer was a UK developed microprocessor with facilities enabling massive parallelism with other transputers. http://www.chilton-computing.org.uk/inf/transputers/p002.htm